<otrdata>
	<mydata>
		<title>Home</title>
		<text><![CDATA[<b>Over-the-Rhine</b> is not only at the center of the Cincinnati community, but it is also at the center of a lot of controversies. This area has become a breeding ground for social issues. Issues of equality, crime, affordible housing, poverty, violence, and economic growth have recently been argued. Although these topics are the current issues facing Over-the-Rhine, this is not the first time many of these issues have been see by Over-the-Rhine. It seems that history is repeating itself once again. So where does the community go from here? Are there any answers. The questions one must consider are simple. Will Over-the-Rhine be in the same position thirty years from now? Is the current Over-the-Rhine community being treated fairly by the city? Do the urbanist movement, the people's movement, and the CDC have the best interests of the community in mind? How can the city deal with these issues without causing a fight within the community? Can Over-the-Rhine become a community where everyone is happy?  ]]></text>
		<cat>Home</cat>
		<image>images/Buddy.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/Buddy.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>A Look into the Over-the-Rhine Community</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>Gentrification is the process by which low cost, physically deteriorated neighborhoods experience renovation and increase property value, along with wealthier residents who displace the original habitats. The occurrence of gentrification is affecting the community of Over the Rhine. Two groups have their perspective on what needs to happen in the community. 3CDC has plans to renovate the community by construction of condominiums which is to help create a stronger and more stable environment; and bring in the upper class of people in the area. The People’s Movement sees things a little differently. They want a stronger community without the fear of displacement. That is renovate the buildings, and make sure that the original residents stay in the community as other class of people move in.</text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/buildingjob.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/buildingjob.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Gentrification: Exile of the Community</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>3CDC’s objective is to undergo an extreme make over, that would rapidly renewal the city’s downtown as the center of both business and residential in the Cincinnati area. The agency is going to capitalize the nation wide trend to reconstruct the historical housing at Over-the Rhine. They also see that there are residential opportunities who seek the downtown life; OTR has hundreds of structures that would be appealing to new residence. There are endless possibilities for these historical buildings according to 3CDC, for example the first floor of these building can be used as retail and residential, and opportunities to produce commercial space, this can be used for retail, office or community services. 3CDC’s first project is under way with the Gateway Condominiums a 6.4 million homeownership project; this will house 26 new condominiums and include two commercial spaces. The project has included 29 parking spaces which are reserve for the purchases of the residential units. Their focus is clear, to identify the houses to be produced, to engage developers (profit and non-profit) who will produce the houses, to examine existing financial institutions for the housing production. The statement that they have indicated is that the new strategy will in no way displace the residents in the OTR area. The goal is set to build an economical and more stable community, that the residents of OTR can be proud.</text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/mansuits.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/mansuits.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Might Makes Right</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>The Peoples Movement has helped the community of OTR for the past 30 years; they see OTR in having a rich history that needs to be preserved, as well as keeping the residents in the community. The fear is that 3CDC with all of the renovations that has taken place, will force the original residents of OTR to move, or be force to move out of their homes. 3CDC is set on the plans that they have devised, which irritates the Peoples Movement. They see that all of the historical building that are turned into condominiums, offices etc. This renovating will force the residents to be moved out, and the new upper class of people to move in. The buildings that 3CDC want to renovate, still have the homeless and low income people in them, and other building are in poor shape to furnish any type of shelter for the hardship of OTR residents, the people’s movement does not want to displace anyone in the community, but to seek affordable housing for them, and to invite different types of classes of people into the community. </text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/march1.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/march1.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Voice of the People</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>The Urbanist vision for Cincinnati is similar to 3CDC, the group sees the community as a stronger region build around a vivacious diversely populated urban foundation. The mission is to repopulate the inner city; the main target is Over-the-Rhine. By building a diverse pedestrian community, the area will attract the young professionals, immigrants, and African American middle class. This type of vision according to the Urbanist will insure a safer community to live, and will insure the stability of the community and bring in the business that is needed for the growth of Over-the-Rhine. </text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/buildingjob.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/buildingjob.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>A Creative Community</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>Over the Rhine is a valuable business district in the heart of Cincinnati. Since this district is so valuable there are many ideas in which people feel that it can be most beneficial to the city. There are three main movements each lobbying their ideas for the communities support. 3CDC wants the community to be developed as corporate business district with large residential housing developments for the upper middle class Cincinnatian. The Urbanist movement is trying to develop middle class housing and promote the arts. The Peoples movement is trying to build within the community to help those inside preserve their homes and culture.</text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/business.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/business.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Business In Over-the-Rhine </subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>This where we put the text 3CDC is a part of an overall system to increase the efficiency and effectiveness of development in Cincinnati. 3CDC has 3 main goals 1) establish organization; 2) develop funding sources; 3) focus on three main areas: Fountain Square, Over the Rhine, and The Banks. They plan to develop Over the Rhine into a business community. They believe the area can be a place where a lot of revenue can be developed from business and upper to middle class housing projects.</text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/3cdc.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/3cdc.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Business:3CDC</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>The Urbanist believe in a strong Cincinnati region built around a vibrant, diversely populated urban core. The Urbanist want to repopulate the center city, especially Over the Rhine by building a diverse pedestrian community. They want to attract young professionals, empty nesters, immigrants, African American households and the creative class. The movement has a focus on middle class housing development of Vine Street and Washington Park. They also want to redevelop housing over commercial spaces. Urbanist believe developing shops for the fine arts and walk ability on the streets will bring a vibrant class to the community.</text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/Urbm.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/Urbm.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Business:Urbanist Movement </subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>City Life and Rhetoric</title>
		<text>The Peoples movement has a focus on keeping the existing people in the community and developing it from the inside. They want to keep outside development from driving away people who already live inside the community. They are willing to accept outside development as long as it involves the community and doesn't drive pre existing members of the community away. They believe in rebuilding the people inside the community with projects in the past like ReStOC that provide job-training for Americorps National Service, Americorps National Civilian Community Corps, and American Association of Retired Persons. Eighty percent of the ReSTOC are community Residents.</text>
		<cat>City Life and Rhetoric</cat>
		<image>images/peom.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/peom.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Busness:People's Movement</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	
	
	<mydata>
		<title>3 Perspectives</title>
		<text>The People’s Movement is a group that is working toward renovating the run down areas of Over-the-Rhine, while keeping the low income individuals in the neighborhoods. The Urbanist Movement is a group that is working toward the integration of housing for all income classes; that will not only pool resources, but pool the creativity of the area. As a result, this will bring up the standard of living in area. 3CDC is a group that is determined to revitalize the neighborhood of Over-the-Rhine. Their main goal is to have a neighborhood that is not only vibrant, but also “ economically and racially diverse.” In order to change the neighborhood they want investors and homeowners to become a part of Over-the-Rhine by pouring their own resources into the neighborhood. After looking at these three groups, one must determine where these three groups stand. Therefore, one must consider the stance of each group on the following questions dealing with the Over-the-Rhine: How did the development of Over-the-Rhine become a problem? What are the origins of this problem? What caused the problem with development of the area? How can these problems be fixed? Can Over-the-Rhine overcome these problems? </text>
		<cat>3 Perspectives</cat>
		<image>images/slums.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/slums.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>The Debate in Over-the-Rhine</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>3 Perspectives</title>
		<text>The People’s main focus is the people in the community of Over-the-Rhine. They are dedicated to rebuilding the city, but also keeping affordable housing for the current individuals living in the area. The last thing that the People’s Movement wants is to displace the current individuals of Over-the-Rhine. As a result, they use rhetoric to persuade their audience to support the individuals living in the community now. They point out that having developers rebuild the area is not going to help the individuals now living there if they are kicked out of their homes. An article in CityBeat captures the type of rhetoric that the People’s Movement uses when discussing the opposing views of the development of Over-the-Rhine. Do not be fooled or taken in by the rhetoric of politicians who would have you believe that 3CDC corporate leaders have better things to do and are simply generously giving their time to a worthy cause…The companies of board members of 3CDC are benefiting financially through their involvement in OTR. Making money is a good thing as long as undue advantage of the public interest is not taken (Taking Undue Advantage of OTR CityBeat). This rhetoric makes the audience think about the motivations of 3CDC. It helps the People’s Movement draw supporters to their cause because their motives are with the people, not the corporations.</text>
		<cat>3 Perspectives</cat>
		<image>images/Equality1.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/Equality1.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>The People's Movement </subtitle>
	</mydata>
	<mydata>
		<title>3 Perspectives</title>
		<text>The Urbanist’s main motivation is to help the area of Over-the-Rhine to thrive through not only ethnic, but economic diversity. This group wants to develop the run down areas of Over-the-Rhine, adding not only affordable housing for low income individuals, but also adding more expensive housing for higher income individuals. In Richard Florida’s “Cities and the Creative Class,” the Urbanist view of gentrification is portrayed. He identifies the “Creative Class” as a group that will, in theory, bring up the living standard of the area, while enabling a cultural exchange of values.</text>
		<cat>3 Perspectives</cat>
		<image>images/urbanist.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/urbanist.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>The Urbanist Movement</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	
	<mydata>
		<title>3 Perspectives</title>
		<text>In 2003, 3CDC came into the picture when “local corporate leaders” hired it to redevelop three areas in the Cincinnati community. The Cincinnati Center City Development Corporation is a nonprofit development group that is slowly developing the area of Over-the-Rhine. The progress that they have made since 2003 can be seen on the edges of the Over-the-Rhine area. They are focused on bringing businesses and higher income individuals into the community. An example of the rhetoric that 3CDC’s uses can be found on the 3CDC website, Over-the-Rhine’s unmatched assets are being tapped to bring significant new investment into the community to strengthen existing businesses and institutions, improve quality of life for residents, and attract new institutions, businesses, residents, and visitors to enjoy all the neighborhood has to offer. Over-the-Rhine boasts the benefits of urban living, feel of a quiet residential community, a wide array of arts and cultural attractions, famous Cincinnati institutions, and a diversity that is found in few neighborhoods anywhere in the country (3CDC website). This rhetoric illustrates 3CDC’s dedication to the community. This is part of their mission statement for the development of Over-the-Rhine. In their statement, they emphasis their intentions of bettering the quality of life that the current residents of Over-the-Rhine have. </text>
		<cat>3 Perspectives</cat>
		<image>images/demolition3cdc.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/demolition3cdc.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>3CDC</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	
	
	<mydata>
		<title>History of Over-the-Rhine</title>
		<text>Over-the-Rhine is located in Cincinnati, Ohio between downtown and Clifton Heights. Over-the-Rhine has supplied a home and jobs for many immigrants to Cincinnati. It is well known for its abundance in Historical buildings and where many people called home. This section of the city plays a huge role in Cincinnati. During the 19th century, Over-the-Rhine became the area where German immigrants decided to settle in Cincinnati, Ohio. They influenced the character of the entire city tremendously. The Germans created an urban community for their homes, stores, churches and small industrial buildings. Since the beginning of the settlement, Over-the-Rhine was the home of poor immigrants, working class families, shop owners and businessmen. Most of these immigrants spoke German and lived a German culture. By the twentieth century, 75% of the people were German-American residents. The Ohio River being located right next to Over-the-Rhine caused the area to develop quickly into an industrial port area. As the area started to develope, the job oppertunities started to develope. Breweries became an important force in industry. Many types of small businesses opened such as grocery stores, bakeries, and lumberyards. In 1855, Findlay market located between Elm and Race Streets, opened. It is the only original public market still operating today. In the last 40 years, Over-the-Rhine has been populated with Appalachian and African-American people. Over-the-Rhine has kept its dense, urban buildings of architectural quality. In 1983 it was listed in the National Register of Historic Places. The city was recognized for its architecture and successful numbers of German immigration in the 19th century (irhine.com).</text>
		<cat>3 Perspectives</cat>
		<image>images/history2.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/history2.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>History</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	
	<mydata>
		<title>3 Perspectives</title>
		<text></text>
		<cat>3 Perspectives</cat>
		<image>images/buildingjob.jpg</image>
		<icon>images/icons/buildingjob.jpg</icon>
		<subtitle>Gentrification: Exile of the Community</subtitle>
	</mydata>
	
	
	
	
</otrdata>